Guide to the Janet Pinkard Papers TAM.300
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Janet Pinkard Papers
1933-1952
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Pinkard, Janet
TAM.300
0.25 Linear Feet in 1 manuscript box
Janet "Ginger" Pinkard was involved in radical activities, mostly in New York City, in the 1930s and 1940s. While attending demonstrations, concerts and films, she collected programs, songsheets and songbooks relating specifically to those events and to radical politics in general. The collection consists of musical and theatrical material. Sheet music, song-sheets and songbooks from a variety of organizations including People's Songs, the Jefferson School of Social Science, Camp Unity and the Worker's Bookshop are included. Also present are programs from the Federal Theatre Project, the American Student Union and other film and theatrical events.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Janet (Ginger) Pinkard in 2001. The accession number associated with this gift is 2001.142.
Arrangement
Folders are arranged alphabetically.
The files are grouped into one series:
Missing Title
I, General Files, 1933-1952.
Historical/Biographical Note
Janet "Ginger" Pinkard was involved in radical activities, mostly in New York City, in the 1930s and 1940s. While attending demonstrations, concerts and films, she collected programs, song-sheets and songbooks relating specifically to those events and to radical politics in general.
Scope and Content Note
The collection consists of musical and theatrical material. Sheet music, song-sheets and songbooks from a variety of organizations including People's Songs, the Jefferson School of Social Science, Camp Unity and the Worker's Bookshop are included. Also present are programs from the Federal Theatre Project, the American Student Union and other film and theatrical events.
Songs, English |z United States |v Texts.; Songbooks.; Programs (documents); Radicalism |z New York (State) |z New York |v Drama.; New York (N.Y.).; People's Songs (Organization); Unity Camp (Wingdale, N.Y.); Federal Theatre Project (U.S.); Progressive Party (U.S.: 1948) -- Songs and music; American Student Union; Camp Midvale (Midvale, N.J.); Pinkard, Janet; Young Communist League of the U.S.; Jefferson School of Social Science (New York, N.Y.)
- Series I: General Files, 1933-1952.
  - Aarons, Saul and Stratton, Mike: "Capitalistic Boss" (sheet music), Jul 1941 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Alexander Nevsky(film): Program, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - American Student Union (ASU): Song-sheets and Programs, May 1940, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Camp Midvale/Nature Friends of America: Artwork, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Camp Unity: Song-sheets (Unity Camp, Wingdale, N.Y.), Aug 25, 1942-Sep 21, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Committee for the Negro in the Arts: "Just a Little Simple" (musical revue program), 1950 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Federal Theatre Project: Programs, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Jefferson Chorus: "Freedom Sings" (program), May 24, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Jefferson School of Social Science: "Ballad for Americans" (song-sheet), undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Liang-Mo, Liu and Modio, Evelyn: China Sings: Folk Songs and Fighting Songs of China(songbook), undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - People's Songs: May Day Songsheets, 1946, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - People's Songs: Progressive Party Song-sheets, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - People's Songs: Songs for Wallace, 2nd Edition (songbook), 1948 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Potamkin, Harry Alan and Rady, Gertrude: Pioneer Songbook: songs for workers' and farmers' children(songbook), 1933 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Red Tanks: Soviet Tank Raiders Behind Nazi Lines(film): Program, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Salt of the Earth(film): Promotional Material, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Worker's Bookshop: Songbooks, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Young Communist League: "Win the War Rally" (program), undated (Box 1, Folder 18)